<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE interface SYSTEM "interface.dtd">
<interface name="NavGraphGeneratorInterface" author="Tim Niemueller" year="2015-2017">
  <constants>
    <enum name="ConnectionMode">
      <comment>Describe how to connect nodes to the graph.</comment>
      <item name="NOT_CONNECTED">
				The node is will not be initially connected.

				The difference to UNCONNECTED is that we do not connect the
				nodes just now, but will do so later, e.g. by adding
				edges. Note that it is an error not to connect the node later.
      </item>
      <item name="UNCONNECTED">
				The node is marked as unconnected and will not be connected to
				another node. This kind of nodes is useful to mark points and
				possibly assign properties without needing to travel to it.

				The difference to NOT_CONNECTED is that the nodes will be
				explicitly marked as not being connected and it is an error to
				connect them.
      </item>
      <item name="CLOSEST_NODE">
				Connect point to the node on the graph closest to the given
				point.
      </item>
      <item name="CLOSEST_EDGE">
				Connect point to the edge in which segment it lies, i.e. search
				for an edge where we can find a perpendicular line going
				through the given point and any point on the edge's line
				segment. If no such segment is found, the point cannot be
				added.
      </item>
      <item name="CLOSEST_EDGE_OR_NODE">
				First try the CLOSEST_EDGE method. If that yields no result,
				use the CLOSEST_NODE method as a fallback.
      </item>
    </enum> 
    <enum name="FilterType">
      <comment>Post-processing filtering type.</comment>
      <item name="FILTER_EDGES_BY_MAP">
				If enabled, filters out all edges after the map generation that
				pass too close by an occupied cell of the map. Use this to get
				rid of connections which "pass through walls".
				Note that this step is done before adding points of interest.
				Therefore edges going to POIs might still pass through or close
				by occupied cells.

				Parameters:
				distance: minimum distance from edges to occupied map grid
				cells to consider it safe.
      </item>
      <item name="FILTER_ORPHAN_NODES">
				If enabled, filters out all nodes which are not connected to
				any other node. These can occur, for example, after performing
				the FILTER_EDGES_BY_MAP filter.
      </item>
      <item name="FILTER_MULTI_GRAPH">
				Sometimes after applying other filters one can end up with
				multiple disconnected graphs. Enabling this filter will keep
				only the largest connected graph and simply remove all nodes
				and edges from smaller graphs not connected to the largest.
      </item>
    </enum>
    <enum name="EdgeMode">
      <comment>
				When adding edges, the mode defines how to add edges.
      </comment>
      <item name="NO_INTERSECTION">
				Only insert edge if it does not intersect with any other
				existing edge in the graph.
      </item>
      <item name="SPLIT_INTERSECTION">
				If the new edge intersects with one or more edges, add new
				points at the intersections and split the edges for this
				point.
      </item>
      <item name="FORCE">
				The edge is added as-is, it may overlap or intersect with
				other edges.
      </item>
    </enum> 
    <enum name="Algorithm">
      <comment>
				Available generator algorithms.
      </comment>
      <item name="ALGORITHM_VORONOI">
	      Voronoi-based algorithm for navgraph generation.
	      This is the default if no algorithm is set.
      </item>
      <item name="ALGORITHM_GRID">
	      Grid-based algorithm with customizable spacing.

	      Parameters:
	      - spacing: the grid spacing in meters
	        (float, m, mandatory)
	      - margin: the minimum distances of edges to obstacles
	        (float, m, mandatory)
	      - add-diagonals: enable adding of diagonal edges in grid cells
	        (bool, optional, default: false)
      </item>
    </enum> 
  </constants>
  <data>
    <comment>
      This interfaces is used to instruct the navgraph-generator.
      It allows to add obstacles and points of interest and perform
      a computation run of the graph generation.

      Operations to modify the parameters (clearing, adding/removing
      obstacles or points of interest etc.) take effect only once a
      ComputeMessage is sent. This can be used, for example, to first
      clear the graph, update it with the latest information, and
      finally generate the graph.

      As soon as any instruction has been received, the generato shall
      only listen to messages from the same sender. Only after a
      computation has been performed can another node send messages
      again.
    </comment>

    <field type="uint32" name="msgid">
      The ID of the message that is currently being processed or
      was processed last.
    </field>
    <field type="bool" name="final">
      True, if the last generation triggered by a ComputeMessage has
      been completed, false if it is still running. Also check the
      msgid field if this field applies to the correct message.
    </field>
    <field type="bool" name="ok">
	    Indicate success (true) or failure (false) of the most recent
	    navgraph generation (valid if final equals true).
    </field>
    <field type="string" name="error_message" length="128">
	    If the "ok" field is false, may give an additional clue about
	    the encountered error.
    </field>
  </data>
  <message name="Clear">
    <comment>
      Remove all currently know obstacles.
      Use this operation with care. A graph generation afterwards will
      yield now results.
    </comment>
  </message>
  <message name="SetAlgorithm">
    <comment>Set algorithm used to generate graph.</comment>
    <field type="Algorithm" name="algorithm">Algorithm to use.</field>
  </message>
  <message name="SetAlgorithmParameter">
    <comment>Set algorithm-specific parameter.</comment>
    <field type="string" name="param" length="32">Parameter name, see
    Algorithm enum description for algorithm-specific
    parameters. Unknown parameters will be ignored.</field>
    <field type="string" name="value" length="64">Value of parameter
    encoded as string. The algorithm will perform the conversion to
    the required data type (e.g., float). An error will make the
    generation fail.</field>
  </message>
  <message name="SetBoundingBox">
    <comment>
      Set the bounding box to use for graph generation. No edge that
      leads outside this bounding box is considered for the graph.
    </comment>
    <field type="float" name="p1_x">X coordinate of bbox start point in global frame.</field>
    <field type="float" name="p1_y">Y coordinate of bbox start point in global frame.</field>
    <field type="float" name="p2_x">X coordinate of bbox end point in global frame.</field>
    <field type="float" name="p2_y">Y coordinate of bbox end point in global frame.</field>
  </message>
  <message name="SetFilter">
    <comment>Enable or disable a post-processing filter.</comment>
    <field type="FilterType" name="filter">Which filter to
    enable/disable.</field>
    <field type="bool" name="enable">True to enable, false to
    disable</field>
  </message>
  <message name="SetFilterParamFloat">
    <comment>Enable or disable a post-processing filter.</comment>
    <field type="FilterType" name="filter">Which filter to
    enable/disable.</field>
    <field type="string" name="param" length="32">Parameter name, see FilterType
    description for possible values.</field>
    <field type="float" name="value">True to enable, false to
    disable</field>
  </message>
  <message name="AddMapObstacles">
    <comment>
      Calculate useful obstacle points from the currently configured map.
    </comment>
    <field type="float" name="max_line_point_distance">
      For points generated on lines found in the map, do not exceed
      this threshold in terms of maximum distance of points on line.
    </field>
  </message>
  <message name="AddObstacle">
    <comment>
      Add an obstacle to be avoided by the graph. The obstacle is
      given as a centroid in X-Y ground-support plane of global frame,
      typical /map frame.
    </comment>
    <field type="string" name="name" length="64">
      ID of the obstacle. Can later be used to remove it again.
    </field>
    <field type="float" name="x">X coordinate of obstacle in global frame.</field>
    <field type="float" name="y">Y coordinate of obstacle in global frame.</field>
  </message>
  <message name="RemoveObstacle">
    <comment></comment>
    <field type="string" name="name" length="64">
      ID of the obstacle to remove.
    </field>    
  </message>
  <message name="AddPointOfInterest">
    <comment>
      Add a point which shall be reachable as a target. The POI is
      given as a centroid in X-Y ground-support plane of global frame,
      typical /map frame.
    </comment>
    <field type="string" name="name" length="64">
      ID of the obstacle. Can later be used to remove it again.
    </field>
    <field type="float" name="x">X coordinate of obstacle in global frame.</field>
    <field type="float" name="y">Y coordinate of obstacle in global frame.</field>
    <field type="ConnectionMode" name="mode">
      The connection mode to use to connect the POI with the graph.
    </field>
  </message>
  <message name="AddPointOfInterestWithOri">
    <comment>
      Add a point which shall be reachable as a target. The POI is
      given as a centroid in X-Y ground-support plane of global frame,
      typical /map frame. This form also accepts a desired target
      orientation for the point.
    </comment>
    <field type="string" name="name" length="64">
      ID of the obstacle. Can later be used to remove it again.
    </field>
    <field type="float" name="x">X coordinate of obstacle in global frame.</field>
    <field type="float" name="y">Y coordinate of obstacle in global frame.</field>
    <field type="float" name="ori">Orientation for target point (rad).</field>
    <field type="ConnectionMode" name="mode">
      The connection mode to use to connect the POI with the graph.
    </field>
  </message>
  <message name="SetPointOfInterestProperty">
    <comment>
      Set a property for an already added point of interest.
    </comment>
    <field type="string" name="name" length="64">
      ID of the point of interest.
    </field>
    <field type="string" name="property_name" length="64">Name of the property to set.</field>
    <field type="string" name="property_value" length="1024">Value of the property
    to set.</field>
  </message>
  <message name="AddEdge">
    <comment>
      Add an edge between two points. Edges for which one of the end
      points does not exist are silently ignored. The points are given
      in the X-Y ground-support plane of global frame, typical /map
      frame.
    </comment>
    <field type="string" name="p1" length="64">ID of first node.</field>
    <field type="string" name="p2" length="64">ID of second node.</field>
    <field type="bool" name="directed">
      True to create a directed edge from p1 to p2, otherwise the edge
      is assumed to be undirected.
    </field>
    <field type="EdgeMode" name="mode">The edge insertion mode.</field>
  </message>
  <message name="SetGraphDefaultProperty">
    <comment>
      Set a graph default property property.
    </comment>
    <field type="string" name="property_name" length="64">Name of the property to set.</field>
    <field type="string" name="property_value" length="1024">Value of the property
    to set.</field>
  </message>
  <message name="SetCopyGraphDefaultProperties">
    <comment>
      Set if the graph default properties should be copied from the
      previous graph. This defaults to enabled and is reset on Clear.
    </comment>
    <field type="bool" name="enable_copy">True to enable copying
    (default) false to disable).</field>
  </message>
  <message name="RemovePointOfInterest">
    <comment>Remove a specific point of interest.</comment>
    <field type="string" name="name" length="64">
      ID of the obstacle to remove.
    </field>    
  </message>
  <message name="Compute">
    <comment>
      Compute the graph with the currently available information.
    </comment>
  </message>
</interface>
