<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE interface SYSTEM "interface.dtd">
<interface name="MongoDBManagedReplicaSetInterface" author="Tim Niemueller" year="2018">
  <constants>
    <enum name="ReplicaSetMemberStatus">
	    <comment>
		    Status for the member of the replica set managed by this
		    instance.

		    Confer
		    https://docs.mongodb.com/manual/reference/replica-states/ for
		    the MongoDB documentation about replica states.
	    </comment>
	    <item name="UNKNOWN">
		    The status has not yet been determined.
      </item>
      <item name="PRIMARY">
	      Member is the primary of the replica set.
	      (MongoDB PRIMARY replica state)
      </item>
      <item name="SECONDARY">
	      Member is a secondary of the replica set.
	      (MongoDB SECONDARY replica state)
      </item>
      <item name="ARBITER">
	      Member acts as an arbiter of the replica set, i.e., it
	      participates in leader elections to break ties but does not
	      replicate data itself.
	      (MongoDB ARBITER replica state)
      </item>
      <item name="NOT_INITIALIZED">
	      The instance is up but has not received a replica set
	      configuration, yet. We expect to join or initiate a cluster
	      soon.
	      (mongo-cxx-driver exception with code NotYetInitialized)
      </item>
      <item name="INITIALIZING">
	      The replica set is currently initializing, e.g., performing
	      the initial data synchronization.
	      (MongoDB replica states RECOVERING, STARTUP2, and ROLLBACK)
      </item>
      <item name="INVALID_CONFIG">
	      The cluster has an invalid configuration. This requires manual
	      intervention, the cluster cannot recover automatically.
	      
	      (mongo-cxx-driver exceptoin with code InvalidReplicaSetConfig)
      </item>
      <item name="REMOVED">
	      The replica set configuration does not mention this
	      instance. Seems we have been removed. It is unlikely this node
	      will join again without intervention.
	      (local instance not found in member list at all)
      </item>
      <item name="ERROR">
	      There has been an error when handling the result, most likely
	      caused by an unknown replica state (for a new MongoDB version).
      </item>
    </enum> 

    <enum name="ReplicaSetPrimaryStatus">
	    <comment>
		    Status of the replica set with regard to a primary.
	    </comment>
	    <item name="PRIMARY_UNKNOWN">
		    Fetching the status failed and we do not know the status
		    regarding a primary of.
      </item>
      <item name="HAVE_PRIMARY">
	      The replica set does have a primary.
      </item>
      <item name="NO_PRIMARY">
	      The replica set currently has no primary.
	      We are going to initiate a leader election shortly.
      </item>
    </enum> 
  </constants>

	<data>
    <comment>
	    MongoDB Managed Replica Set Statis.
	    The mongodb plugin can manage replica sets, i.e., it can
	    bootstrap them for initial setup and add and remove replica set
	    members dynamically. This interface provides status information.
    </comment>
    <field type="ReplicaSetMemberStatus" name="member_status">
	    The current status of the managed member of the replica set.
    </field>
    <field type="ReplicaSetPrimaryStatus" name="primary_status">
	    Status of the replica set regarding a primary.
    </field>
    <field type="string" length="1024" name="error_msg">
	    A message describing an error in more detail.
    </field>
	</data>
</interface>
