<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE interface SYSTEM "interface.dtd">
<interface name="NavigatorInterface" author="Martin Liebenberg" year="2007">
  <data>
    <comment>
      The navigator interface is used by the navigator to export information about
      the current status of the navigator and to define all messages by which the navigator
      can be instructed.

      There are three coordinate systems, the robot system which is a right-handed cartesian
      coordinate system with the robot in its origin, X axis pointing forward, Y pointing to
      the left and Z pointing upwards. The second coordinate system is the so-called
      navigator system. It is a coordinate system similar to the robot system, but the
      origin is defined on the initialization of the navigator. The last system is the
      odometry system. It is again a similar system, but the origin is reset from time
      to time and the robot's position in this system gives the odometry deltas.
    </comment>

    <field type="float" name="x">Current X-coordinate in the navigator coordinate system.</field>
    <field type="float" name="y">Current Y-coordinate in the navigator coordinate system.</field>

    <field type="float" name="dest_x">X-coordinate of the current destination, or 0.0 if no target has been set.</field>
    <field type="float" name="dest_y">Y-coordinate of the current destination, or 0.0 if no target has been set.</field>
    <field type="float" name="dest_ori">Orientation of the current destination, or 0.0 if no target has been set.</field>

    <field type="float" name="dest_dist">Distance to destination in m.</field>

    <field type="unsigned int" name="msgid">The ID of the message that is currently being
      processed, or 0 if no message is being processed.</field>
    <field type="bool" name="final">True, if the last goto command has been finished,
      false if it is still running</field>
  </data>
  <message name="Stop">
    <comment>Stop motion immediately.</comment>
  </message>
  <message name="Turn">
    <comment>Turn around own major axis. Opposed to setting a goto with a target
    angle this message causes the robot to turn exactly by this angle, it will
    not normalize it and turn to a specified angle.</comment>
    <field type="float" name="angle">Angle of the turn.</field>
    <field type="float" name="velocity">The desired turning velocity in rad/s,
      set to zero to use default value.</field>
  </message>
  <message name="CartesianGoto">
    <comment>States the next target to navigate to.</comment>
    <field type="float" name="x">X-coordinate of the target, in the robot's coordinate system.</field>
    <field type="float" name="y">Y-coordinate of the target, in the robot's coordinate system.</field>
    <field type="float" name="orientation">The orientation of the robot at the target.</field>
  </message>
  <message name="PolarGoto">
    <comment>States the next target to navigate to.</comment>
    <field type="float" name="phi">Angle between the robot's front and the target.</field>
    <field type="float" name="dist">Distance to the target.</field>
    <field type="float" name="orientation">The orientation of the robot at the target.</field>
  </message>
  <message name="MaxVelocity">
    <comment>States the maximum velocity of the robot for driving/walking, but not for turning.</comment>
    <field type="float" name="velocity">Maximum velocity of the robot.</field>
  </message>
  <message name="Obstacle">
    <comment>Adds an obstacle within the scan area. It's just for the Navigator GUI.</comment>
    <field type="float" name="x">X-coordinate of the obstacle.</field>
    <field type="float" name="y">Y-coordinate of the obstacle.</field>
    <field type="float" name="width">Width of the obstacle.</field>
  </message>
  <message name="ResetOdometry">
    <comment>Resets the origin of the odometry system</comment>
  </message>
</interface>
