<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE interface SYSTEM "interface.dtd">
<!-- $Id$ -->
<interface name="ObjectPositionInterface" author="Tim Niemueller" year="2007">
  <constants>
    <!-- Note that the type constants are saved in a 16 bit wide unsigned int and thus have
         to be in the range [0..65535] -->
    <constant type="unsigned int" value="0" name="OTHER">
      This constant denotes an object that cannot be denoted by any other constant.
    </constant>
    <constant type="unsigned int" value="1" name="BALL">
      This constant denotes a ball object.
    </constant>
    <constant type="unsigned int" value="2" name="OPPONENT">
      This constant denotes an opponent robot.
    </constant>
    <constant type="unsigned int" value="3" name="TEAMMEMBER">
      This constant denotes a robot of the same team.
    </constant>
  </constants>
  <data>
    <comment>
      This interface provides access to arbitrary object positions and velocities. You
      can use it to store the position of any object in the RoboCup domain. There is a type
      indicator for the RoboCup soccer domain to easily distinguish several well
      known objects. You may choose not to use this for other application in which case
      the value should be other (which is also the default).
    </comment>
    <field type="unsigned int" name="object_type">
      Object type, use constants to define
    </field>
    <field type="char" name="supports_relative">
      1 if the current interface in general has support for relative position data.
    </field>
    <field type="char" name="supports_global">
      1 if the current interface in general has support for global (world) position data.
    </field>
    <field type="char" name="has_relative">
      1 if the current interface at the moment has valid relative position data.
    </field>
    <field type="char" name="has_global">
      1 if the current interface at the moment has valid global (world) position data.
    </field>
    <field type="bool" name="visible">
      True, if object is visible.
    </field>
    <field type="float" name="yaw">
      Angle between the robot's forward direction and the object on the ground plane.
      This angle is in a local 3D coordinate system to the robot and given in radians.
    </field>
    <field type="float" name="pitch">
      Angle between the robot's center position on the ground plane and the middle point
      of the object (e.g. this denotes the height of the object combined with the distance.
      The angle is given in radians.
    </field>
    <field type="float" name="distance">
      Distance from the robot to the object on the ground plane. The distance is given
      in meters.
    </field>
    <field type="float" name="dyp_covariance" length="9">
      Covariance of Distance/Yaw/Pitch values. This is a 3x3 matrix ordered line by line,
      first three values represent row, next tree values second row and last three values
      last row from left to right each.
    </field>
    <field type="float" name="world_x">
      This is the X coordinate in the cartesian right-handed world coordinate system.
      This coordinate system has its origin in the center of the field, Y pointing to
      the opponent's goal and X pointing to the right.
    </field>
    <field type="float" name="world_y">
      This is the Y coordinate in the cartesian right-handed world coordinate system.
      This coordinate system has its origin in the center of the field, Y pointing to
      the opponent's goal and X pointing to the right and Z pointing downwards.
    </field>
    <field type="float" name="world_z">
      This is the Z coordinate in the cartesian right-handed world coordinate system.
      This coordinate system has its origin in the center of the field, Y pointing to
      the opponent's goal and X pointing to the right.
    </field>
    <field type="float" name="relative_x">
      This is the X coordinate in the cartesian right-handed robot coordinate system.
    </field>
    <field type="float" name="relative_y">
      This is the Y coordinate in the cartesian right-handed robot coordinate system.
    </field>
    <field type="float" name="relative_z">
      This is the Z coordinate in the cartesian right-handed robot coordinate system.
    </field>
    <field type="float" name="xyz_covariance" length="9">
      Covariance of WorldX/WorldY/WorldZ values. This is a 3x3 matrix ordered line by line,
      first three values represent row, next tree values second row and last three values
      last row from left to right each.
    </field>

    <field type="float" name="extent">
      Extent of the seen object.
    </field>

    <field type="float" name="yaw_velocity">
      Gives the velocity of the object for yaw in radians per second.
    </field>
    <field type="float" name="pitch_velocity">
      Gives the velocity of the object for pitch in radians per second.
    </field>
    <field type="float" name="distance_velocity">
      Gives the velocity of the object distance meter per second.
    </field>
    <field type="float" name="dyp_velocity_covariance" length="9">
      Covariance of Distance/Yaw/Pitch velocityvalues. This is a 3x3 matrix ordered line by
      line, first three values represent row, next tree values second row and last three
      values last row from left to right each.
    </field>

    <field type="float" name="world_x_velocity">
      Velocity of object in the world coordinate system in X-direction in meter per second.
    </field>
    <field type="float" name="world_y_velocity">
      Velocity of object in the world coordinate system in Y-direction in meter per second.
    </field>
    <field type="float" name="world_z_velocity">
      Velocity of object in the world coordinate system in Z-direction in meter per second.
    </field>
    <field type="float" name="xyz_velocity_covariance" length="9">
      Covariance of WorldX/WorldY/WorldZ valocity values. This is a 3x3 matrix ordered line
      by line, first three values represent row, next tree values second row and last three
      values last row from left to right each.
    </field>

  </data>
</interface>
