<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE interface SYSTEM "interface.dtd">
<interface name="SwitchInterface" author="Tim Niemueller" year="2008">
  <data>
    <comment>
      This interface provides access to LEDs. The interface controls
      an intensity value between 0.0 (off) and 1.0 (on, max
      intensity). LEDs that do not support intensity setting can only
      be set to on and off.
    </comment>
    <field type="bool" name="enabled">
      True if the switch is currently enabled.
    </field>
    <field type="float" name="value">
      If switches support multiple states these can be indicated with
      this value. For example for a switch that notes the intensity it
      could be a value in the valid range.
    </field>
    <field type="float" name="history">
      This value records the number of seconds a switch has been
      enabled continuously -- or not. The time is recorded in
      seconds. A positive value indicates time the switch was turned
      on, a negative value indicates the time (when converted to the
      absolute value) the button has not been pressed. Zero means
      "just initialized".
    </field>
    <field type="unsigned int" name="short_activations">
      Number of consecutive short clicks (turned on). Can be used to recognize
      patterns of clicks. This is an optional field.
    </field>
    <field type="unsigned int" name="long_activations">
      Number of consecutive short clicks (turned on). Can be used to recognize
      patterns of clicks. This is an optional field.
    </field>
    <field type="unsigned int" name="activation_count">
      Number that is to be incremented whenever a short or long activation
      happened. Can be used to decide if a change in status happened.
    </field>
  </data>
  <message name="Set">
    <comment>For switches that support setting via software this
      message allows for setting the current state.</comment>
    <ref>enabled</ref>
    <ref>value</ref>
  </message>
  <message name="EnableSwitch">
    <comment>For switches that support setting via software this
      message turns the switch on.</comment>
  </message>
  <message name="DisableSwitch">
    <comment>For switches that support setting via software this
      message turns the switch off.</comment>
  </message>
  <message name="EnableDuration">
    <comment>Enable switch for a specified duration only. The value
      can optionally be set. Note that not all SwitchInterface writers
      must or can support this.
    </comment>
    <field type="float" name="duration">Duration in seconds for which
    the switch should be enabled.</field>
    <ref>value</ref>
  </message>
</interface>
